<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Herb Susmann</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Herb Susmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Herb Susmann {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint: Flexibly Modeling Shocks in Demographic and Health Indicators</title>
      <link>/news/flexibly-modeling-shocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/flexibly-modeling-shocks/</guid>
      <description>I and Leontine Alkema have a new preprint available, Flexibly Modeling Shocks to Demographic and Health Indicators with Bayesian Shrinkage Priors. We discuss how to build models for estimating and projecting demographic and health indicators that exhibit large short-term fluctuations, which we call shocks, using Bayesian shrinkage priors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint: Targeted Provider Profiling</title>
      <link>/news/targeted-provider-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/targeted-provider-profiling/</guid>
      <description>We now have a new preprint available, Doubly Robust Nonparametric Efficient Estimation for Provider Evaluation, co-authored with Yiting Li, Mara A. McAdams-DeMarco, Iván Díaz, and Wenbo Wu. We develop doubly robust estimators for causal parameters relevant to evaluating the performance of healthcare providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Preprint: Longitudinal Average Treatment Effects on the Treated</title>
      <link>/news/longitudinal-average-treatment-effects-on-the-treated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/longitudinal-average-treatment-effects-on-the-treated/</guid>
      <description>We recently released an updated preprint of our work on longitudinal generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated based on longitudinal modified treatment policies. The updated preprint is titled Longitudinal Generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated for Multi-valued and Continuous Treatments and is co-authored by Nicholas T. Williams, Kara E. Rudolph, and Iván Díaz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication: Adaptive Conformal Inference in COMPUTO</title>
      <link>/news/computo-aci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/computo-aci/</guid>
      <description>I recently had an article published in COMPUTO, a journal of the French Royal Statistical Society, titled AdaptiveConformal: An R Package for Adaptive Conformal Inference. The article was cowritten with my collaborators Antoine Chambaz and Julie Josse.
COMPUTO has an interesting publication process that focuses on reproducibility. We wrote the manuscript as an R Quarto document, and we were required to submit a link to the Github repo so reviewers could verify reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talk: Bayesian Targeted Learning at ISBA 2024</title>
      <link>/news/isba-2024-bayesian-targeted-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/isba-2024-bayesian-targeted-learning/</guid>
      <description>Chiesa di San Simeon Piccolo, Venice, Italy.
 I had a wonderful time attending ISBA 2024 in last week, held at the Ca&#39; Foscari University of Venice. I had the opportunity to present at the invited session &amp;ldquo;Novel and Flexible Bayesian Approaches for Causal Inference in Complex Settings&amp;rdquo;, which was organized by Mike Daniels and Maria Josefsson and chaired by Arman Oganisian. The slides and speaker notes for my talk can be found here: Targeted Bayesian Learning for Causal Inference: The Best of Both Worlds?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
