<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Herb Susmann</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Herb Susmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Herb Susmann {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Publication: Quantile Super Learner in CSDA</title>
      <link>/news/quantile-super-learner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/quantile-super-learner/</guid>
      <description>Antoine Chambaz and I had our work on Quantile Super Learner published in Computational Statistics &amp;amp; Data Analysis. We establish theoretical guarantees for Super Learner ensembles (also known as model stacking) built to estimate conditional quantiles, and apply the method to some real-world applications relevant to solar forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication: B-splines Transition Models in JRSS-C</title>
      <link>/news/splines-jrss-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/splines-jrss-c/</guid>
      <description>Leontine Alkema and I had our article on flexible modeling of demographic transitions using B-splines published in JRSS-C. This approach is now used in the Family Planning Estimation Tool for estimation and projection of family planning indicators; more details are available in a preprint led by Leontine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at PAA 2025</title>
      <link>/news/paa-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/paa-2025/</guid>
      <description>There was a lot of statistical demography activity at PAA this year, centered around three consecutive sessions on Saturday morning. I gave a talk on my work with Leontine Alkema on using Bayesian shrinkage priors to handle shocks in demographic and health indicators; the slides are available online. Adrian Raftery also presented our work on projecting refugee and asylum seeker populations, which is available on ArXiv as a preprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talk: Generalized ATTs at ENAR 2025</title>
      <link>/news/enar-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/enar-2025/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of visiting ENAR for the first time to give a talk on our work on generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated to longitudinal settings. Slides and speaker notes for my talk can be found here: Longitudinal Generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated for Multi-valued and Continuous Treatments</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication: Probabilistic Predictions of Emergency Department Arrivals</title>
      <link>/news/emergency-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/emergency-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Our paper Probabilistic prediction of arrivals and hospitalizations in emergency departments in Île-de-France was published in the International Journal of Medical Informatics. We used a combination of ensemble learning and Adaptive Conformal Inference to predict emergency department arrivals and hospitalizations in and around Paris.
This paper builds on some previous theoretical work establishing that Super Learner can be applied for estimating quantiles in online settings (preprint available at https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19343).
We also used our R package AdaptiveConformal for Adaptive Conformal Inference, described in our paper in COMPUTO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprints: Family Planning Estimation Model and Shrinkage Data Models</title>
      <link>/news/family-planning-preprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/family-planning-preprints/</guid>
      <description>Two new preprints out today related to our work on Bayesian hierarchical models for demographic and health indicators.
The first preprint, joint with Leontine Alkema and Evan Ray, introduces a data model that incorporates Bayesian shrinkage priors as a way to flexibly handle data sources with reporting issues. We have also used shrinkage priors for modeling indicators with large shocks (for example, life expectancy during wars); see our preprint.
The second preprint, led by Leontine, gives an overview of the current iteration of the Family Planning Estimation Model (FPET), which incorporates extensions that I worked on for my dissertation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint: Causal Distributional Random Forests</title>
      <link>/news/2024-11-14-causal-drf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2024-11-14-causal-drf/</guid>
      <description>Jeffrey Näf and I have a new preprint available on ArXiv, Causal-DRF: Conditional Kernel Treatment Effect Estimation using Distributional Random Forest. We took some of Jeff&amp;rsquo;s previous work on building distributional random forest&amp;rsquo;s and adapted it to the case of estimating kernel treatment effects. Jeff contributed the heavy-duty theory and I worked on the coding and simulation studies &amp;ndash; a good partnership!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint: Flexibly Modeling Shocks in Demographic and Health Indicators</title>
      <link>/news/flexibly-modeling-shocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/flexibly-modeling-shocks/</guid>
      <description>I and Leontine Alkema have a new preprint available, Flexibly Modeling Shocks to Demographic and Health Indicators with Bayesian Shrinkage Priors. We discuss how to build models for estimating and projecting demographic and health indicators that exhibit large short-term fluctuations, which we call shocks, using Bayesian shrinkage priors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint: Targeted Provider Profiling</title>
      <link>/news/targeted-provider-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/targeted-provider-profiling/</guid>
      <description>We now have a new preprint available, Doubly Robust Nonparametric Efficient Estimation for Provider Evaluation, co-authored with Yiting Li, Mara A. McAdams-DeMarco, Iván Díaz, and Wenbo Wu. We develop doubly robust estimators for causal parameters relevant to evaluating the performance of healthcare providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Preprint: Longitudinal Average Treatment Effects on the Treated</title>
      <link>/news/longitudinal-average-treatment-effects-on-the-treated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/longitudinal-average-treatment-effects-on-the-treated/</guid>
      <description>We recently released an updated preprint of our work on longitudinal generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated based on longitudinal modified treatment policies. The updated preprint is titled Longitudinal Generalizations of the Average Treatment Effect on the Treated for Multi-valued and Continuous Treatments and is co-authored by Nicholas T. Williams, Kara E. Rudolph, and Iván Díaz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication: Adaptive Conformal Inference in COMPUTO</title>
      <link>/news/computo-aci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/computo-aci/</guid>
      <description>I recently had an article published in COMPUTO, a journal of the French Royal Statistical Society, titled AdaptiveConformal: An R Package for Adaptive Conformal Inference. The article was cowritten with my collaborators Antoine Chambaz and Julie Josse.
COMPUTO has an interesting publication process that focuses on reproducibility. We wrote the manuscript as an R Quarto document, and we were required to submit a link to the Github repo so reviewers could verify reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talk: Bayesian Targeted Learning at ISBA 2024</title>
      <link>/news/isba-2024-bayesian-targeted-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/isba-2024-bayesian-targeted-learning/</guid>
      <description>Chiesa di San Simeon Piccolo, Venice, Italy.
 I had a wonderful time attending ISBA 2024 in last week, held at the Ca&#39; Foscari University of Venice. I had the opportunity to present at the invited session &amp;ldquo;Novel and Flexible Bayesian Approaches for Causal Inference in Complex Settings&amp;rdquo;, which was organized by Mike Daniels and Maria Josefsson and chaired by Arman Oganisian. The slides and speaker notes for my talk can be found here: Targeted Bayesian Learning for Causal Inference: The Best of Both Worlds?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
